

BACK-END DEVELOPER AND DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR

I'm a skilled Back-End Developer and Database Administrator with a focus on creating efficient, reliable systems. I enjoy working with others to build strong solutions and am committed to sharing my expertise with the developer community

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Letmegrab By NearBy (Node JS Developer)

Augest 2024 (Currently Working)

At LetMeGrab, I am currently contributing to an e-commerce-like platform that connects individual sellers with a large user base. The platform facilitates product sales through a focused, user-friendly interface. My role is to enhance back-end logic and streamline communication between buyers and sellers, ultimately promoting a thriving online marketplace.

Instance IT Solutions (Associate Node JS Developer)

January 2024 - June 2024

During 8th semester internship at Instance IT Solution, I worked on a Hospitality Management System. Myresponsibilities involved developing APIs for core functionalities, creating cron jobs for automation and scheduled tasks, optimizing database queries, and refactoring backend code. Additionally, I focused on inventory management to ensure real-time tracking and management of hotel resources. The technologies I utilized were Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and JavaScript.

CoderKube Technologies (Associate PHP Developer)

July 2023 - December 2023

During my 7th semester internship at CoderKube Technologies, I worked on a project called ImageLab. My role involved connecting editors and customers based on user requirements to streamline the process of image editing. I implemented AJAX for asynchronous data rendering, which improved the user experience by reducing page load times and server requests. The technologies I used for this project were PHP, Laravel, SQL, and AJAX.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelors - Computer Engineering

Sarvajanik College Of Engineering And Technologies (SCET) 2021 - 2024

Diploma - Computer Engineering

Tapi College Of Engineering And Technologies (Dharukawala) 2018 - 2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python Frameworks & Libraries: React, Node.js Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools & Platforms: Git

Other Skills: REST APIs, Test-Driven Development, Agile methodologies

INTEREST & PERKS

Reading Books (Specially self helping or philosophical)
Playing Chess
Finding Solution of real time problem
Communication with client
Multilingual
Architecture Designing